hi there I'm Luis Gomez with Palo Alto Education
你好  我是来自Palo Alto Education 的路易斯·戈麦斯
and i'd like to teach you
我想教你
how to make your very own
如何做你自己的
rock-paper-scissors plain program using machine learning
剪刀石头布平面程序  通过使用机器学习
so this is gonna be a very fun project
所以这将是一个非常有趣的项目
and we're gonna learn a ton
我们将学习许多
about the fundamentals of machine learning
关于机器学习的基本原理
so why rock-paper-scissors
所以我们为什么会选择剪刀石头布呢？
well humans aren't that great at it
其实人们并不是很擅长这个游戏
I mean seriously
我可没开玩笑
so what I'm envisioning is
所以我所设想的是
a program that can do a little bit better than this
一个擅长这个游戏的项目
so something more along these lines
所以是与一想法相关的一些事儿
that's what I'm talking about you know
这就是我所说的  你知道的
bring on anybody bring on the rock paper scissors world champion
让所有人 让石头剪刀布的世界冠军 来和他比赛
we can take him on
我们可以带他去
no problem with this program that we're gonna build
我们设计的程序无懈可击
so how do we do this
所以我们如何做到这一点呢？
well let's let's think a little bit
让我们 让我们想一想
let's start breaking it down a little bit
让我们开始想想如何拆分步骤
thinking about what our goals for this program should be
想想我们这个程序的目标是什么
so obviously someone cuz I know someone's going to come up to the computer show Rock
我知道的  一定会有人来到电脑面前  出石头
the computer is going to return paper
电脑则会出布
somebody's going to come up to the computer show the paper shape
也会有人对着电脑出布
and the computer is going to return scissors
电脑会则会出剪刀
you get the idea
你应该明白了吧 就是这样
but the biggest problem here is
但最大的问题是
get the computer to recognize images
让计算机识别图像
how how can we do that you know
我们应该怎么做到呢？
how can we teach a computer to recognize shapes and images
我们怎样才能教会电脑识别形状和图像呢？
how can we how can we do that
我们怎样才能做到这样呢？
how was it possible
这可能吗？
how can a computer understand something
电脑怎么可能会理解这些呢？
how can it get the idea of something
电脑又怎么能接受这些想法呢？
so we're gonna use a very common thing
所以我们使用了一个非常常见的工具
that we use in machine learning called training data
那就是我们经常在机器学习中使用的训练数据
so this is a super key concept for machine learning
这是机器学习中至关重要的概念
it's having a lot of training data
机器学习中有大量的训练数据
today we're gonna be using images
今天我们将使用图像
because rock paper scissors is obviously an image based a visual based game
因为很明显剪刀石头布是一个基于图像与视觉的游戏
so for example one piece of training data
例如一条训练数据
we might have is a picture of somebody doing the rock symbol
可能是某人在做石头手势的照片
and a label this is very important with training data
以及它的标签  对于训练数据来说这非常重要
each piece of data also has to come with its own label
每一条数据中必须包含它自己的标签
so we take this image of rock
所以对于石头的这个图像
we take our label that says rock
我们给它的标签就为石头
literally
按照字面
just the word rock
就是石头的意思
and we're gonna pass this into our machine learning model
我们会把这个置入我们机器学习的模型中
and we want to get a bunch of these okay
并且我们需要得到大量的这些数据
we want one for each label
我们想要一个我们将拥有的每个标签
we're gonna have three labels
我们需要三个标签
because there's three possible outcomes in rock-paper-scissors
因为在这一游戏中  有三种可能产生的结果
well three possible moves I should say in rock-paper-scissors
或者说在石头剪刀布中  有三个可能的动作
you've got rock paper scissors
你可能得到石头 剪刀 或布
so we want to make sure
所以我们要确保
we get plenty of images for each of these three labels
对于这三个中的每一个标签  我们都得到了足够多的图像
so image of paper make sure we label it paper
所以如果是布的图像  记得标记为布
hand it off to the computer
同样再把它录入电脑
another image of rock label at rock
若是石头的图像  那么标签就为石头
hand it off to the computer
然后录入电脑
image of scissors label at scissors
剪刀的图像就标记为剪刀
pass it off to the computer
然后录入电脑
and so on so we're gonna keep doing this over and over and over again
就这样一遍遍地重复
and the more training data we get and
以及我们得到的训练数据越多
the more varied it looks
看起来越多样
the better our model is going to perform in an actual game of rock-paper-scissors
我们的模型在实际的游戏中也会表现得更好
and we'll talk a little bit more about that later
我们稍后会再细谈
but let's start getting into this project and setting everything up
现在让我们进入这个项目 开始设置吧
so we can right away just start writing down some code
所以我们可以马上写代码啦
so let's get started
让我们开始吧
we're gonna open up a new browser tab and
打开一个新的浏览器选项卡和
we're gonna go to machinelearningforkids.co.UK
然后进入“machinelearningforkids.co.UK”（为孩子设计的机器学习）这个网址
you can just search machine learning for kids into Google
你也可以在google页面中输入“machinelearningforkids”，
or whatever and the website will come up so
或者无论什么浏览器  然后网页就会出来啦
we're gonna click on worksheets here and
我们要点击这里的工作表
we're gonna scroll down till we see our project
然后向下滚动  直到看到我们的项目
should be right here rock paper scissors
应在就在这个位置 剪刀石头布
and click on download
然后点击“download”（下载）
where a student so we're gonna click download project worksheet
在“student”（学生）这一栏下  我们要点击“download project worksheet”（下载项目工作表）
let that download
让它下载吧
and while that's happening we're gonna go over here
这种情况经常会发生  然后我们来到这儿
click log in okay
点击“log in”（登录）还好现在我已经
now I've got the worksheet pulled up already and
我现在已经得到了工作啦
this is exactly what the worksheet says to do
我们刚刚做的  正是工作表告诉我们要做的步骤
so I'm just walking you through this worksheet already
所以我只是带你看一遍这个工作表
if you want to pull it up and follow along
可能你会需要放大页面  然后跟着指示走
we're just gonna be walking through this
但我们现在只是快速过一遍
so click on log in I'm gonna log in real quick and
点击“log in”（登录）  我会快速登录
we're gonna go to your projects
然后我们点击“go to your projects”（你的项目）
so let's add a new project
点击“add a new project”（添加新项目）的按钮
and we're gonna title it
然后给它命名
rock paper scissors
石头 剪刀 布
and recognizing like we said the type of data we're going to be using is images
还记得吗 我们说过 我们将会使用的数据类型 是图像
so make sure to click images right here
所以一定要点击“image”（图像）
and click create
然后单击“create”（创建）
and there's our project so they're gonna open that up
这就是我们的项目啦  如果要打开它
just click on that
只需要点击它
go to train click this little train button right here
找到“train”（训练）  点击这里的训练按钮
so right here see this button
看到这个按钮所要求的了吗
where it says add me a new label
它在说  请给我添加新标签
like we said earlier we're gonna want three labels
正如我们之前说过  我们需要三个标签
rock paper scissors
石头 剪刀 布
we'll just start off with one so let's click add new label
我们就先从其中一个开始  点击“add new label”（增加新标签）
and we're gonna write Rock and add
然后我们要写下“rock”石头  并点击“add”添加
so there's that and since we want to
就是这样  因为我们想要
you know we want it to play against real humans
你懂的  我们希望它能与真人对抗
okay we want to get somebody sitting next to us to play against our program
我们希望坐在我们旁边的人  能与我们的程序对抗
and have our program kick their butt
并让我们的程序打他个落花流水
so we want to take pictures ourselves of rock paper scissors
所以我们需要摆出石头剪刀布的手势  并拍照
so we're gonna click on webcam
所以我们要点击网络摄像头
you might get something up here
你可能会看到一个对话框跳出  访问摄像头的许可询问
asking you to allow access to your webcam just click allow
只需点击“allow”（允许）即可
and because I'm recording my screen right now
因为我正在用摄像头录制我的屏幕
I'm not able to use my webcam
所以我无法使用我的网络摄像头
but you will be able to just
但你可以只用
follow along with this worksheet
跟随这个工作表上的步骤
right here click webcam click allow
像这里说明的  点击“webcam”（网络摄像头） 点击“allow”（允许）
we just did that and now you're gonna click this add button right here
我们已经完成了  现在你只要点击这个“add”（添加）的按钮
ok and you know
以及 你知道的
make your make your hand into a fist shape for Rock
让你的手握成拳头的形状
and click Add and just fill this up
单击“add”（添加）  然后只需把这一块空白填满
take like ten pictures of rock
拍摄10张照片左右
and I'm gonna go do that real quick
我接下来就要去快速完成做这件事
and I'll be right back alright
我会马上回来的  好吧
so hopefully you've got all your rock images
所以希望你也已经得到了你的石头的图像啦
let's add a new label now of paper
现在让我们添加一个新的标签 —— 布
I'm gonna click add and click on webcam over here
点击“add”（添加） 然后点击这里的“webcam”（网络摄像头）
and ah there I am so
啊... 看到我啦！
you know what to do you know what to do
你知道该做了  对吧
make the paper symbol hold it up to your webcam at different angles
摆好布的手势  然后以不同的角度伸向摄像头
use a different hand you know
然后用另一只手重复之前的动作
yeah so we're gonna take ten pictures of the paper symbol
然后我们再拍10张布的手势照片
and we're gonna come back
我们还会再回到这一步
we're gonna do the same exact thing with the scissors
我们摆出剪刀的手势  做同样的事情
but so let's get let's get ten pictures of paper
所以让我们一起先得到10张布的手势照片吧
great
完成啦
so you've got your ten images of rock
所以你有10张石头的图像了可能
maybe you've got more if you do that's awesome
可能你拍了更多  如果是的话  那简直太棒了
at least ten images of paper and
至少十张布的图像
we're gonna add a new label here
点击这里的“add a new lable”（增添新标签）按钮
type in scissors and if you spell it wrong
输入剪刀  如果你拼写错了
you can just come up here delete it
可以点击这里  删除它
click yes try again so we're gonna add a new label of scissors
点击  再试一次  所以我们要添加一个新的剪刀标签
boom add boom click on webcam boom
点击“add”（增加）  点击“webcam”（网络摄像头）
you know what to do
你知道接下来要做什么 对吧
scissors from different angles different hands different rotations
不同角度的剪刀的手势  左右手都要 旋转变换
so if we take a picture of some things face
所以当我们在拍脸的照片时
or like a desk
或是向桌子一样的东西
or a crayon or something I don't know
或是蜡笔  或一些我不知道的东西
and we label it as scissors
然后我们将其标记为剪刀
our computer is gonna think that's what scissors look like
我们的电脑会认为剪刀就长这个样子
and we don't want that
我们不希望如此
so if you take a picture of something other than scissors on accident
所以如果你不小心拍了一张不是剪刀的照片
click that little red X there
点击那个红色的X
get rid of it and that takes care of that
删除它  所以我们要细心一些
so yeah I'll just get ten at least ten of scissors
是的  我会拍10张  至少10张剪刀的照片
and different rotations
不同的旋转角度
get that done
完成后
and we'll be right back
我们马上回来
great so we've got all the images that we need now
太棒了  所以我们已经得到了所有需要的图像
all we're gonna do is back out of here
我们现在需要做的就返回  离开这个页面
click on back to project
点击“back to project"（返回项目）
go to learn and test
点击“learn and test”（学习和测试）的按钮
so this is going to be where we actually feed all of the images and labels
所以我们的图片与标签会全部存储到这块区域
that we created into our machine learning model
而这些图片与标签  就是我们为机器学习的模型所创建的
so it can start learning
然后电脑就可以开始学习
and getting an idea of what rock paper and scissors all mean
并了解石头 剪刀 布 分别是什么意思
so to do that we're just gonna click this one symbol button here
那样做我们只是点击这个按钮
train your machine learning model
即“train your machine learning model”（训练你的机器学习模型）
and there we go so
我们继续往下看
training will take awhile
培训需要一段时间
and even though we've only got around 30 pictures or so
即使我们只有大约30张左右的照片
it'll still take a while
它还是会需要一段时间
because there's a lot of complicated math happening in the background right now
因为后台正在进行有很多复杂的计算
the math and algorithms behind what we're doing right now
里面蕴含的数学和算法
aren't so important
其实并不是那么重要
as the high-level ideas
重要的是高层次的理念
the idea of having training data
也就是训练数据的理念
associated with labels and passing this off to a model
详细点说就是  设计标签并传递此信息给模型
and letting it do all of the complicated math for us
并让它完成所有复杂的计算工作
and getting an idea of
并且取得理解
what each of our labels means
每一个标签分别表示的是什么
or in this case what each of our labels will look like
在这次的学习中  即每个标签指代的是什么形状
oh great
太棒了
looks like our model is done training
看起来我们的模型已经完成了训练
cool so our model is ready to test
所以我们的模型已经做好准备  可以测试了
oh man this is exciting isn't it
乡亲父老们  这是多么令人兴奋的时刻啊
I'm excited I actually haven't tested it yet
太激动了  实际上我之前还没有测试过它
so this is gonna be my first time seeing it too
所以这也会是我第一次看到它运行
pop up in the webcam
弹出网络摄像头的窗口吧
oh let's see
让我们看一下
Wow~~~  with only 10 I'm actually astounded by that
哇塞~~~ 尽管只用了10张图片  我真的很震惊
76% is good now that our models in training
76% 的确认率 已经非常棒了
let's continue with this worksheet
让我们继续这个工作表
great so we've now got our trained model
太棒了  所以我们已经得到了我们的训练模型
we're gonna make the final logic for our rock-paper-scissors robot
我们将要为我们的“石头剪刀布”机器人做最后的逻辑训练
to beat any human
这样就可以打败人类了
even the rock-paper-scissors world champ
甚至是我们的石头剪刀布的世界冠军
we're gonna do that right now so let's scroll up right here
现在就这样做吧  把滚动条往上拉到这儿
click back to project and
点击“back to project”（返回项目）
we are gonna open scratch
然后打开“scratch”
I'm gonna click this open in scratch button
点击这个“open in scratch”按钮
oh I need flash you might need to enable this as well
我需要flash运行  你可能也需要开启它
give this one second to load
等一秒钟加载
cool so now that we've got scratch open
现在我们的“scratch”页面已经打开了
we're just gonna follow along with this worksheet
我们接下来只需要按照这个工作表执行
make sure we've got some blocks right here
确保这里有一些小方块
which we do if we've got rock paper scissors and recognized image
如果已经获得了石头剪刀布 以及识别过图像 那么这里就会出现小方块
cool so if you've got some extra blocks there
所以如果你有一些额外小方块
don't worry about it
也不用担心
it's not going to be an issue as long as we've got rock paper scissors
这没什么关系  只要其中有石头 剪刀 布
and recognized image label blocks
以及“recognized image”（已识别图像）的标签
we'll be good
那就很棒啦
so go over here to project templates
然后来到这个“project templates”（项目模板）
and look for rock paper scissors sweet alright so now
寻找石头剪刀布  太好了
that we've got scratch open
我们已经打开“scratch”页面了
we're just gonna follow the instructions on the worksheet
我们只需要遵循工作表的指令
nice and simple
很棒  并且挺简单的
so pay mention to what the blocks are doing
所以请注意  小方块代表的动作含义
think through as you're reading the worksheet
当你在阅读工作表时，请仔细思考
what... each block you're putting down is is happy is doing
我们正在把这些小方块放在这个位子  开心吧
so we're gonna code this up real quick
我们会快速编码
so I'll code this up
所以我会编码
I won't show you step by step how to do it
我不会一步一步教你怎么做
I'll leave some of that exploration to you
我会留下一些给你自己探索的空间
a little out of focus
镜头有点失焦
there there we go
好啦
and yeah just to get you started
只是教你们如何开始
you're gonna want to go over to the result sprite
跳转至“result” 角色
just like it says right here so
按这儿的指示
you're gonna click on result
点击“result”（结果）
go up here to events to find this color of block
往上移  来到“events”（事件）栏这儿  找到这种颜色的小方块
that says when I receive and just drop it in right here
按它所说的  当我收到时  只需要把它放在这儿
let's full screen this so you can see better
放大全屏  这样你们就可以看得更清楚些
when I receive you're gonna click this drop-down
当我收到时  你要点击这个下拉列表
click score
点击“score”（分数）
and that's how you get that block
就这样你就可以得到
that's the basic idea of scratch
这是scratch中最基本的观念
so yeah just match up the colors
是的  只需要匹配这些颜色
match up the different blocks
匹配不同颜色的方块  如果你需要的话
and if you need help with the colors ask a friend
如果你不擅长于辨认颜色  你也可以问下朋友
or ask your teacher but yeah I'll let you code this up
或者你的老师  不过 当然 我会让你编码的
and I'll be right back with all of the code complete
我会带着所有完整的编码 马上回来
alright so hopefully you've got all that code down
好啦  希望你们把所有的代码都记下来啦
we're gonna continue following along with the worksheet
我们要继续跟进这个工作表
and click on the you sprite which is down here
并单击这里“Sprite”栏目下的“you” 按钮
click on you
点击“you”
and just check real quick yeah
只是快速检查下
we're gonna click on the costumes tab and
要点击“costume”（服装）的标签
let's do a new costume and
让我们做一个新的服装
we're gonna do new costume from camera and
点击相机图表  做新的服装
this is let's click allow' on this allow again
让我们点击“allow”（允许） 再次点击“allow”（允许）
and this is going to be the move that
进过这一步之后
we present the our AI with our machine learning robot with
我们同意展示我们AI（人工智能） 和会机器学习的机器人
so let's take a picture of
让我们拍一张照片
I'll do scissors it doesn't matter
我做剪刀的手势  不过这没关系
do whatever move you want
你可以做任何你想要的动作
whatever you think you can you can win with
只要是你觉得你会赢的招式
all right let's take this scissors picture
好吧  让我们出剪刀的图片
all right so I got my scissors picture
我已经得到了我的剪刀图片
we're gonna keep following along
我们会继续跟进
to do click on the scripts tab and
点击“script”（脚本）标签
we're gonna finish up some final code blocks here
在这里完成一些最终的代码块
and we'll be ready to go up against our
我们将准备去对付我们那
super smart trained machine learning model
经过智能训练过的超级机器学习模型
right here Oh back to the scripts tab
就在这里 哦 回到“script”（脚本）选项卡
and we are just going to add the following script blocks
我们接下来要添加以下脚本块
so I'm gonna add some code blocks in real quick
我要快速添加一些代码块
I'll let you do that at your own pace
你可以按照自己的节奏慢慢来
I'm gonna pause the video real quick
我会快速暂停
and do that
并执行此操作
and I'll be right back
我会马上回来
all right that one was much easier than the first set of code blocks
这一个比第一个系列的代码块容易得多
so we had to add
所以我们需要添加
so now we're just going to make sure
所以我们现在要确保
to save our project go to file save project
保存我们的项目  进入“file”（文件）标签栏  点击“save project”（文件保存）
just save our project
只需要保存我们的项目
somewhere easy to reach like the Downloads folder
至比较容易找到的地方  比如“Downloads folder”（下载文件夹）
call it rock-paper-scissors
命名为石头剪刀布
a default name is fine cool
默认的名称也是不错的  太棒了
so we've now saved our scratch file
所以我们已经保存了我们的“scrtach”文件
which is connected to our machine learning model
它可以连接到我们的机器学习模型
and now it's time to test let's see
现在是时候测试了  让我们看看
how well that our model can play against a real-life human
看看我们的模型有多厉害  可以对抗真人
so all we're gonna do is click go
所以我们要做的就是点击“go”
and that's it this is gonna be this is the final test
对 就是点击他 这将会是终极测试
let's see let's see how well our computer performs
看看我们的电脑表现得如何
gets the real human being three two one
与真人比赛会如何呢？ 三 二 一
he's cheating he's cheating
他作弊  他在作弊！
he's definitely cheating I don't believe that for one second
他绝对是作弊的   我脑子进水了才会相信他呢
reset reset
重来  重来
alright I'm just I'm just messing around now
好吧  我刚刚是在戏弄它
but you can see it's recognizing scissors
但你可以看到它的已经识别出了剪刀
like we we confirmed that earlier
就像我们之前确认过的那样
that it was recognizing
它识别出了这一点
so when we did the little scissors test
所以当我们做了剪刀的小测试时
so it's working you've got your rock paper scissors about here
所以他是成功识别的  你也获得了剪刀石头布的游戏程序啦
and if you want to change the computer settings
如果你想要改变电脑的设置
okay yeah it's actually picking
哇 对极了 它实际上是在挑选
so the codes actually picking random between rock paper and scissors
它实际上是在随机挑选石头 剪刀 布
we can make it so that the computer wins every time
电脑可以每次都赢  因为其实这是我们可以设计的
but you know this is good enough to show us
但是你知道这是一个很棒的展示形式
how the machine learning model works
它告诉我们机器学习的模型是如何运作的
so remember the big idea behind all of these
所以请记住所有背后的重要理念
pull the worksheet back up
把工作表拉回来
is we had training data with labels
我们有带有标签的训练数据
we passed this training data and the labels into
并将此训练数据和标签放入
our machine learning model
我们收集的机器学习模型
it gathered information about each piece of training data
它会搜集所有有关的训练信息
so for all of the data that was labeled Rock
所有对于所有那些被标记为石头的数据
our model learned different curves
我们的模型学到了不同曲线
different lines different colors
不同线条  不同的颜色
different shapes for rock
以及不同石头手势的形状
did the same thing for paper and for scissors
对于布和剪刀 也都是一样的原理
and now it's using that to recognize scissors
现在要用它来识别剪刀
right here boom just pretty cool so
你看这儿  酷毙了吧
that's the rock paper scissors project
这就是石头剪刀布的项目
I hope you enjoyed it and
我希望你能喜欢它
I hope you keep reading and learning more about machine
我希望你保持阅读和学习更多关于机器学习的知识
and completing more of these projects
并能完成更多的此类项目
because they're super fun
因为他们真的超级有趣